





Machine Learning Engineer

WHO AM I?

I'm a B.Sc Computer Science student at Amirkabir University of Technology. I have worked as an Android Developer and Backend Developer for several years before taking on management responsibilities. Currently, I'm researching and studying Machine Learning, with a particular emphasis on Deep Learning and Natural Language Processing.

LANGUAGES

English - proficient Persian - native Turkish - native

EXPERIENCE

1/2020 - Current

Machine Learning Engineer

intelliSearch

I've experimented with and researched modern architectures such as Transformers, built a scalable neural search engine for multilingual texts for semantic text search (intellisearch.ir), and worked on multi-modal models such as CLIP and its applications for semantic photo search from text prompts. For serving and deploying models efficiently, I used ONNX to reduce the model size and increase inference speed, and also used a Redis-based architecture to enable scaling and load-balancing. Docker was also used for ease of deployment. I've also contributed to the open-source community by creating libraries:

- · Lite Inference Toolkit (LIT) for PyTorch
- Memory Efficient Attention O(sqrt(n)) for Jax and PyTorch

PyTorch / ONNX / JAX / Sklearn / Uvicorn

1/2022 - 3/2022

Machine Learning Engineer - Intern

UZH - KrauthammerLab

Designed an abstract tracking engine for tracking a machine learning pipeline - artifacts, metrics, logs, and parameters

Python / MLFlow / Meta-Programming

8/2020 - 9/2021

Lead Software Engineer (Backend)

Tray

Managed a Technical Team of 3+ size for more than one year developing infrastructure and applications with Scrum and Modern Agile Methodologies at Trayl which is an Online Intercity Transportation Solutions Startup. The system is carefully designed to be scalable and work with high efficiency under heavy loads.

Node.js / TypeScript / PostgreSQL / GraphQL / Docker

9/2017 - 9/2020

Software Engineer (Backend)

Freelance

Worked as Freelance Backend Developer for 3+ years handling more than 8+ projects.

Go / Node.js / Python / C / Redis / PostgreSQL / MongoDB / graphQL, gRPC / Docker

1/2016 - 9/2020

Android Developer

Freelance

Worked as Freelance Android Developer for more than 4 years, completing 15+ Android projects. Used Android NDK to implement interfaces between C and Java for performance-sensitive operations

Java / Kotlin / Android NDK / RxJava / OpenGL

EDUCATION

9/2018 - Current Computer Science Bachelor's Degree

Amirkabir University of Technology

Current GPA: **18.3/20**

9/2014 - 6/2018 High School Diploma - Mathematics

Shahid Madani 2 High School

GPA: 19.41/20